Lorien (LO-ree-en) Smyer

Jr. Full Stack Web Developer

http://lorienmcs.github.io github.com/LorienMCS twitter.com/lorienmcs

www.linkedin.com/in/loriensmyer lorienmcs.wordpress.com lorienmcs@gmail.com

SUMMARY

My recent completion of a five and a half month, 70 hour per week web development program demonstrates my ability to work hard and efficiently absorb material.

My years of work experience as a bookkeeper and Internet researcher honed my high level of attention to detail, and increased my skills in identifying and fixing errors, problem-solving, and quickly finding accurate

I have a passion for learning, and for helping to create successful results.

SKILLS

FRONT-END: JavaScript, Angular S, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX BACK-END: Rails, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Express, EJS

TOOLS: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Jasmine, Slack, Sublime Text

DESIGN: Photoshop, Illustrator

ADDITIONAL SKILLS: Research, Writing

EDUCATION

Galvanize

Full Stack Web Development

2015

Studied Javascript, Angular, jQuery, Node, Express, HTML, CSS, Rails, Ruby, Test Driven Development, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and other tools and skills in Galvanize's 24-week Full Stack Web Development Program.

Peralta Colleges (Berkeley City College, College of Alameda, Laney College, Merritt College) Cumulative GPA: 3.9/4.0

1988 - 2014

Courses in CSS, HTML, Web Design and E-Commerce, Java, C#, Photoshop, Illustrator, MS Office, Accounting, Micro-Economics, Macro-Economics, Ecology, Writing, West African Dance, Spanish.

City College of San Francisco

1990 - 1991

Courses in Linguistic Anthropology, African History, Music, Botany. Tutored students in Music Fundamentals.

University of California, Santa Cruz

1982 - 1983

Courses in Electronic Music, Art, Jazz History.

PROJECTS

You-ish (demo: http://youish.herokuapp.com, code: https://github.com/LorienMCS/You-ish)

Capstone project for the Full Stack Program at Galvanize. Users can enter their first name and month and day of birth, and are shown interesting data related to their input. Built using Angular, Bootstrap, Javascript, and multiple APIs.

Angular Shopping Cart App (demo: http://lorienmcs.github.io/angular_2_8,

code: https://github.com/LorienMCS/angular 2 8)

Project for the 18th week of the Full Stack Program at Galvanize; built using Angular, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.

Angular Reddit Clone (demo: http://lorienmcs.github.io/angular_7, code:

https://github.com/LorienMCS/angular_7)

Project for the 17th week of the Full Stack Program at Galvanize; built using Angular, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.

SF Map App (demo: https://sfmapapp.herokuapp.com, code: https://github.com/LorienMCS/map app two) Project for the ninth week of the Full Stack Program at Galvanize; built using Google Maps JavaScript API, Express, EJS, Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Bootstrap, and JavaScript, to design a map of San Francisco that users can log into and add places they think are interesting, and comment on other users' places.

EMPLOYMENT

Stonehouse California Olive Oil

January 2014 - June 2014

Bookkeeper, Office Assistant, Website Editor and Social Media Correspondent

- -Edited website directly and gave instructions to website designers using correct HTML and CSS code, decreasing website maintenance costs.
- -Audited retail daily sales and proactively corrected credit card discrepancies, resulting in increased customer satisfaction.
- -Maintained accurate inventory records for company website and Amazon store so out of stock product was not mistakenly sold, increasing both efficiency and customer satisfaction.

Responsibilities included website editing, recipe card editing and layout, social media including Facebook, Twitter, and Pinterest, A/R, A/P, auditing. Operating systems and software used included Photoshop, QuickBooks, MS Office.

T324 Website Design and Development

August 2013 - January 2014

Finance Manager and Office Administrator

-Audited customer support accounts and invoiced customers for previously unbilled support hours, resulting in increased revenue.

Responsibilities included A/P, A/R, payroll, auditing, computer maintenance.

Streetlight Records

June 1998 - January 2014

Bookkeeper & Internet Researcher

-Raised D&B PAYDEX score through timely payment of invoices, which helped Streetlight to establish direct relationships with major labels.

Internet researcher and part of a three-person team of bookkeepers for Streetlight Records' three stores. Responsibilities included A/P, auditing, database management for co-op advertising, computer hardware installation, software troubleshooting, payroll processing, payroll tax deposits.

Fast Access Systems

1988 - 1994 & 1998 - 1999

Office Manager

-Found and corrected errors in employee timesheets, ensuring accurate employee compensation. Responsibilities included invoicing the University of California and other clients, payroll, A/P, P&L statement, office equipment research and purchase.

Landry Wildwind, LCSW

1988 - 1998

Bookkeeper

- -Researched, purchased and installed computer hardware and software; instructed employer and employees in usage of computer applications.
- -Initiated move from manual to computerized bookkeeping, resulting in a more complete financial picture and increasing oversight and efficiency.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Featured Blog Post on Website and in Newsletter

September 2015

Women Who Code

My blog post about the first Tech Inclusion Conference was featured on the WWC website (https://www.womenwhocode.com/blog/80) and in their CODE Review newsletter.

Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

March 2013 - December 2014

Peralta Colleges

The international honor society for community colleges. Must have at least a 3.5 GPA to be eligible.

National Dean's List

1991

City College of San Francisco